KIMBERLY JENKS

PERSONAL DETAILS
BIRTH: Torrance, California
MARITAL STATUS: Single
CITIZENSHIP: U.S.A.
MOTHER TONGUE: English



CONTACT INFO

PHONE: +56 (2).631.969.25

E-MAIL: kimberly_jenks@hotmail.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Upon receiving my TESOL certification, I worked as a guest substitue teacher for an elementary and high school public school district in order to further develop my teaching skills and apply the techniques I acquired with LCC during my TESOL certification. Throughout my time working as a substitute teacher, mentor, and hotel supervisor, I have developed the ability to supervise, direct and guide individuals and groups in the completion of tasks and fulfillment of goals. In addition, my vast business experience in education and the hospitality industry has trained me in the expertise and use of interpersonal skills for resolving conflict, relating to and helping people.

I recently graduated from San Diego State University, California with a bachelor's in International Business. It was at this prestigious institution that I was encouraged and gained the strong educational background skills to think outside the box and work with individuals of all nationalities. My degree in international relations and my extensive previous management experience allows me to anticipate the needs of my students and meet those needs in a professional and proficient manner.

Prior to receiving my TESOL certification, I spent a semester studying abroad in Spain and living with local Spanish students. Upon completion of my semester abroad, I traveled throughout Europe for two months. These experiences allowed me the opportunity to immerse myself in different cultures while learning a new language; this amazing experience also has instilled in me the passion to help others overcome language barriers.

I am confident that as an ESL teacher my related skill sets and commitment to grow and excel will be of great value to my students.

EDUCATION

TESL/TESOL Certification

2010 LCC University of San Diego, California

Bachelor of Liberal Arts & Sciences in International Business

2010 San Diego State University, California

- Specialization in Management
- Emphasis in Spanish language

Study Abroad Program

2009 Universidad Antonio de Nebrija, Madrid, Spain

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Substitute Teacher | Carbon County School District | 2010-2011

While preparing to relocate to Santiago, I worked as a substitute teacher for the Carbon Country School District for three months. Carbon Country School District includes five elementary schools, two middle schools, and one high school. I alternated as a guest teacher for various class levels ranging from kindergarten through grammar school and all the way up through high school levels. I routinely had to have prearranged lesson plans prepared in situations when the regular teacher did not have sufficient time to prepare the lesson. In addition, I had to build a rapport with a vast age of students ranging from 5 years old to 17 years old within a short time frame. My skills for following direction were utilized when multiple times I had to follow a teacher's lesson plan for the day and execute the plan using skills learned in my training such as ESA (engage, study, activate).

Payroll & Human Resources Administrator | Excel Hotel Group | 2009-2010

Excel Hotel Group is a management company that oversees and operates twelve hotels throughout the United States. During the year I worked for this company I was solely responsible for processing and overseeing payroll procedures for all twelve hotels. In addition, I ran the human resources department which included duties such as interviewing job candidates, new hire orientation and paperwork, process terminations, and respond to unemployment case files. I routinely visited hotels to present seminars and information to the employees regarding benefits such as medical insurance, vacation, and retirement. This aspect of the job allowed me to develop strong profession presentation skills. It also offered the opportunity to further my bilingual language skills because all the presentations needed to be given in English as well as Spanish.

Sales Manager | Residence Inn Marriott Mission Valley | 2006-2008

At this prestigious hotel chain, I began as a front desk agent. Shortly thereafter I was promoted to front desk manager and within six months I was trained and working as a sales manager for government, group, and corporate sales bookings. As a front desk manager I gained skills in leadership, leaming how to oversee my associates, and just as importantly, how to delegate responsibility when necessary. As a sales manager, I had to be well organized and know how to identify what my clients needed and how to suit each client's needs individually as well as their group's needs.

Career Services Executive Assistant | College of Eastern Utah | 2004-2006

This was a key position where I acquired extensive skills in organization and attention to detail. I was responsible for processing all new hire paperwork and maintaining employment files for all students working at the College of Eastern Utah. In addition I created spreadsheets and organized data needed to fulfill the state of Utah education requirements. I was able to cultivate my creative streak through job postings and marketing advertisements for the department.

Mentor for Children with Mental Illness | Frontier Project | 2003-2006

Through the Frontier Grant Project, I developed and designed a youth volunteer program for high school youth to mentor young children suffering from mental illness. I attended extensive training on rapport building, counseling, and educating atrisk youth. Through my weekly group activities with the children as well as my one-on-one weekly mentoring meetings with specific at-risk children, I developed not only the ability to manage and counsel large groups of 7-12 year olds but also the skills to tutor on an individual level. Many of the youths in the program were from underprivileged backgrounds where their access to quality education was often limited. Therefore, a substantial degree of patience and sensitivity was demanded. By planning fun activities, establishing a strong rapport and mentoring a few of the students one-on-one, I succeeded in creating an enjoyable experience where the children could develop and leam ways to handle their behavioral setbacks.

RELEVANT ACQUIRED SKILLS

Leadership, Management and Organizational Skills: I pride myself on my ability to listen to the clients' needs, make decisions with my superiors and execute those decisions by leading a team of hospitality workers. I coordinate these tasks in a timely matter by delegating and motivating with respect.

Research and Planning Skills: Diligent planning has been critical to the success of the sales and marketing approaches I have overseen. Part of this process involves creating new ideas with regards to advertisement design and seasonal promotions, as well as the targeting key customer markets. In addition, my ability to plan comprehensively has allowed me to forecast and react quickly to potential problems.

Human Relations Skills: While working closely with various managers, executives, age groups, and children with mental illness I developed an ability to establish and maintain rapport, cooperate, be sensitive and intuit others' feelings. Moreover, I often trained and counsel those new to Excel Hotel Group.

Language Skills: I became fluent in Spanish when I attended university in Madrid, Spain. I used these language skills subsequently while working for hotel companies as well as living in San Diego where there is a large population of Spanish speakers.

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES

Jason Everson | Vice President of Operations | Excel Hotel Group | jeverson@excelhotelgroup.com | +001.858.621.4908

Lindsey Lanham | Assistant General Manager | Residence Inn Marriott Mission Valley | +001.619.881.3645

Thompson Mosher | General Manager | Hyatt Summerfield Suites El Segundo | +001.310.725.0100

PERSONAL REFERENCES

Adrienne Hutchinson | TESL/TESOL Teacher | praxidice@gmail.com |

Dr. Corey Ewan | Professor | College of Eastern Utah | corey.ewan@ceu.edu | +001.435.650.7843

Bill Gutierrez | Senior Vice President | Progressive Management Systems | bill@pmscollects.com | +001.909.518.5417